A Guide to the Charles F. Gillette, Papers, ca. 1880-1985 (bulk 1918-1969)
Library of Virginia
- Photographs, ca. 1880-1969 (bulk 1920-1960).
  - Vesper, F. W. A.- CCN 1206 (Box 101, Folder 7)
    Gillette account number: 348; Photographs: 12; Notes: See also oversize photographs
  - Villa Susadie (Box 101, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Historical Society, 1931- CCN 844 (Box 101, Folder 9)
    Gillette account number: 421; Photographs: 1
  - Washington Inaugural Centennial Celebration, 1889 (Box 101, Folder 10)
    Gillette account number: None; Photographs: 2
  - Weddell, Alexander- CCN 876 (Box 101, Folder 11)
    Gillette account number: 300; Photographs: 6
  - Williams, T. C. - See also oversize photograph file.- CCN 912 (Box 101, Folder 12)
    Gillette account number: 307; Photographs: 7; Notes: See also oversize photographs
  - Miscellaneous Gardens (Box 101, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs (Box 101, Folder 14)
    Gillette account number: None; Photographs: 15
  - Blow, George P. - "Deer Park" - La Salle, Il (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Blow, George P.- CCN 170 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    Gillette account number: 56; Photographs: 2
  - Blow, George P.- CCN 170 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    Gillette account number: 56; Photographs: 17
  - Blow, George P.- CCN 170 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    Gillette account number: 56; Photographs: 21
  - Brady, Mrs. Nicholas- CCN 1204 (Box 102, Folder 5)
    Gillette account number: 327, 380, 389, 390; Photographs: 5
  - Bryan, Jonathan- CCN 1106 (Box 102, Folder 6)
    Gillette account number: 19, 439, 698; Photographs: 1
  - Davidson College- CCN 179 (Box 102, Folder 7)
    Gillette account number: 790; Photographs: 3
  - Dunn, McKee- CCN 205 (Box 102, Folder 8)
    Gillette account number: 218; Photographs: 8
  - Gillette, Charles F. - 105 East Cary St.- CCN 985 (Box 102, Folder 9)
    Gillette account number: 446; Photographs: 4
  - Gillette, Charles F. - Early Office (Box 102, Folder 10)
  - Gillette, Ellen C.- Costume Photograph (Box 102, Folder 11)
  - Gillette, Ellen C. - Wedding Portrait (Box 102, Folder 12)
    Gillette account number:; Photographs: 1
  - Hayes, John G.- CCN 339, 1202 (Box 102, Folder 13)
    Gillette account number: 50, 940, 667, 458; Photographs: 9
  - Jeffress, Robert- CCN 1207 (Box 102, Folder 14)
    Gillette account number: 391; Photographs: 15
  - Knight, Floyd- CCN 422 (Box 102, Folder 15)
    Gillette account number: 246; Photographs: 1
  - Niedringhaus, Mrs. Hayward- CCN 1209 (Box 102, Folder 16)
    Gillette account number: 343; Photographs: 1
  - Northrop, Mrs. William- CCN 567 (Box 102, Folder 17)
    Gillette account number: 1; Photographs: 1
  - Ortman, Randolph- CCN 1126 (Box 102, Folder 18)
    Gillette account number: 106; Photographs: 23
  - Parrish, J. Scott- CCN 600 (Box 103, Folder 1)
    Gillette account number: 104, 179; Photographs: 14
  - St. Isaac Jogues Novitiate (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Taylor, J.P - Monument Ave.- CCN 988 (Box 103, Folder 3)
    Gillette account number: 16; Photographs: 5
  - Unidentified Costume Party (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Vesper, F. W. A.- CCN 1206 (Box 103, Folder 5)
    Gillette account number: 348; Photographs: 4
  - William and Mary College- CCN 904 (Box 103, Folder 6)
    Gillette account number: 180; Photographs: 2
  - Williams, T. C.- CCN 912 (Box 103, Folder 7)
    Gillette account number: 307; Photographs: 12
  - Zinn, Mrs. F. C.- CCN 952 (Box 103, Folder 8)
    Gillette account number: 59; Photographs: 4
  - Miscellaneous Gardens (Box 103, Folder 9)
- St. Giles Church Files, 1937-1967.
  Series VIII is housed in five (5) archival boxes on shelf and arranged alphabetically by folder title. Included in this series are sermons, correspondence, deeds, plats, meeting minutes, membership rolls, church committee papers, and financial materials. This series deals with Gillette's work in the establishment, construction, and administration of St. Giles (Presbyterian) Church in Richmond, Virginia. Gillette was a crucial member in the creation of the church after a dogmatic schism within the congregation of Richmond Grace Covenant Church. As one of the original St. Giles elders, a member of the construction committee, and a Sunday School teacher, Gillette contributed inestimable value to the church congregation. Also included in this series are materials related to Dr. John Blanton Belk, the controversial preacher and missionary whose sermons precipitated the split within Grace Covenant Church.
  - Architectural Drawings, Deeds, and Property Plats, 1939-1954 (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Ballou & Justice, Architects, 1945-1952 (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - Belk, Dr. J. Blanton, Correspondence, 1938-1957 (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Belk, Dr. J. Blanton, Sermons, 1950 (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Budget and Finance, 1937-1963 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Building Committees, 1937-1956 (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - Church Buildings and Equipment, 1938-1948 (Box 106, Folder 1)
  - Church Buildings and Equipment, 1949 (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - Church Buildings and Equipment, 1950-1953 (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - Church Buildings and Equipment, 1954-1959 (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - Church Furnishings, 1937-1948 (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - Church Furnishings, 1949 (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - Church Furnishings, 1950-1961 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Church Grounds, 1938-1962 (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - Committees, Clubs, Guilds, 1938-1964 (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - Congregational Meetings, 1937-1949 (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - Construction Specifications, 1947 (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - Construction Specifications, 1947-1950 (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, General, 1937-1940 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, General, 1941-1967 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Deacons and Elders, 1937-1954 (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - East Hanover Presbytery, 1937-1957 (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - Grace Covenant Church, 1937-1938 (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - Membership Rolls and Lists, 1937-1959 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - Ministers, Substitute, 1940-1960 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Morris, DuBois, Jr., 1944 (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - Organ and Piano, 1940-1952 (Box 108, Folder 9)
  - Presbyterian Committee of Religious Education and Publication, 1938-1945 (Box 108, Folder 10)
  - Programs from Services, 1937-1963 (Box 108, Folder 11)
  - Publications, 1939-1952 (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - Sessions Meetings, Minutes, 1938 Jan-Jul (Box 109, Folder 2)
  - Sessions Meetings, Minutes, 1938 Aug-Dec (Box 109, Folder 3)
  - Sessions Meetings, Minutes, 1939-1952 (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - Sessions Meetings, Minutes, 1953 and n.d. (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Westhampton Theater, 1940 (Box 109, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1939-1962 (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 8)
- Vendors and Sub-Contractors, 1915-1968 (bulk 1936-1966).
  Series IX is housed in seven (7) archival boxes on shelf and arranged alphabetically by folder title. Included are catalogs, promotional literature, and company information from firms with which Gillette did business or that were soliciting projects from the landscape architect. Individual firms are listed separately by name with general materials grouped alphabetically within the folder listing.
  - A General- Catalogs 1943-1956 (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - Anchor Post Fence Co. 1937-1941 (Box 109, Folder 2)
  - Andrews Geyser 1939-1960 (Box 109, Folder 3)
  - Atlas Fence Co. n.d. (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - B General- Catalogs 1936-1953 (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Bay State Nurseries 1950-1953 (Box 109, Folder 6)
  - Bobbink & Adkins 1932-1957 (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - Boxwoods 1939-1962 (Box 109, Folder 8)
  - Bulbs 1936-1962 (Box 109, Folder 9)
  - Burpee Seed Co. 1965 (Box 109, Folder 10)
  - C General- Catalogs 1939-1963 (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Cold Frames n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - Colored Concrete and Brick 1950-1956 (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Cyclone Fence Co. n.d. (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - D General- Catalogs 1936-1965 (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - Doggett-Pfeil Co. 1956-1957 (Box 110, Folder 6)
  - Drafting Supplies n.d. (Box 110, Folder 7)
  - Dreer's 1948-1952 (Box 110, Folder 8)
  - Du Pont n.d. (Box 110, Folder 9)
  - Erkins Studios, Inc. 1946-1965 (Box 110, Folder 10)
  - F General- Catalogs 1915-1966 (Box 110, Folder 11)
  - F. Graham Williams 1943-1962 (Box 110, Folder 12)
  - Fireplaces 1947-1948 (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Fiske Iron Works n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - G General- Catalogs 1932-1963 (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Garden Furniture- Metal n.d. (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - Griffing Nurseries 1948-1949 (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - H General- Catalogs n.d. (Box 111, Folder 6)
  - Habitant Fence, Inc. 1961 (Box 111, Folder 7)
  - Hammacher Schlemmer 1963-1964 (Box 111, Folder 8)
  - Hemlock Bark Extract 1931-1940 (Box 111, Folder 9)
  - Herbs n.d. (Box 111, Folder 10)
  - Inertol Co., Inc., Swimming Pool Division 1958-1959 (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - Insecticides n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2)
  - J General- Catalogs 1940-1943 (Box 112, Folder 3)
  - Jackson & Perkins Co. 1958-1963 (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - James Rare Plant Nursery 1955 (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Johan C. Van Reisen 1949-1951 (Box 112, Folder 6)
  - Kelsey-Highlands Nursery 1946 (Box 112, Folder 7)
  - Kenneth Lynch, Inc. 1937, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 8)
    Note: See also oversize
  - King's Nursery 1943 (Box 112, Folder 9)
  - L General- Catalogs 1943-1954 (Box 112, Folder 10)
  - Lakeland Nurseries Sales 1963 (Box 112, Folder 11)
  - Le-Mac Nurseries 1941 (Box 112, Folder 12)
  - Lindley Nurseries, Inc. 1961 (Box 112, Folder 13)
  - Little Tree Nursery 1959 (Box 112, Folder 14)
  - Lorio Iron Works n.d. (Box 112, Folder 15)
  - M General- Catalogs n.d. (Box 112, Folder 16)
  - Mayhew Shop n.d. (Box 112, Folder 17)
  - Mecklenburg Nurseries, Inc. 1949 (Box 112, Folder 18)
  - Meierjohan-Wengler Metalcraftsmen n.d. (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Messelaar Bulb Co., Inc. 1965-1968 (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - Michigan Peat, Inc. n.d. (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Mitsch, Grant E. 1957-1961 (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - N-O General - Catalogs 1937-1954 (Box 113, Folder 5)
  - Oak Park Nurseries 1952 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Old Fort Camellia and Azalea Nursery 1951 (Box 113, Folder 7)
  - Orton Plantation Nursery 1952-1955 (Box 113, Folder 8)
  - P General- Catalogs 1930-1958 (Box 113, Folder 9)
  - Pitzonka's Pansy Farm n.d. (Box 113, Folder 10)
  - Plantation Gardens n.d. (Box 113, Folder 11)
  - Playground Equipment n.d. (Box 113, Folder 12)
  - Pompeian Studios 1952-1958 (Box 113, Folder 13)
  - Porter, Knox D. 1958 (Box 113, Folder 14)
  - R General - Catalogs 1937-1951 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Rainbird Sprinklers 1958 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Rambusch Decorating Co. 1952 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Richmond Cedar Works n.d. (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Rohloff & Co. 1960-1961 (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Ruffin & Payne, Inc. 1948 (Box 114, Folder 6)
  - Russell Gardens 1956-1957 (Box 114, Folder 7)
  - Ryereson Steels 1954-1957 (Box 114, Folder 8)
  - S General- Catalogs 1938-1963 (Box 114, Folder 9)
  - Seal, Inc. 1945-1965 (Box 114, Folder 10)
  - Skinner Irrigation Co. 1946-1958 (Box 114, Folder 11)
  - Sprayers and Sprinklers n.d. (Box 114, Folder 12)
  - Statuary- Design Drawings n.d. (Box 114, Folder 13)
  - Stewart Iron Works Co. n.d. (Box 114, Folder 14)
  - Sundials- Design Drawings n.d. (Box 114, Folder 15)
  - Swimming Pools and Equipment n.d. (Box 114, Folder 16)
  - T-U General- Catalogs n.d. (Box 114, Folder 17)
  - V General- Catalogs 1949 (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Van Hof & Blokker 1951-1953 (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - Van Hof & Blokker 1954-1956 (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - Van Hof & Blokker 1957-1959 (Box 115, Folder 4)
  - Van Hof & Blokker 1960-1964 (Box 115, Folder 5)
  - Vick's Wildgardens n.d. (Box 115, Folder 6)
  - W General- Catalogs 1943-1964 (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - Walter Marx Gardens 1960-1964 (Box 116, Folder 2)
  - Watkins Nurseries 1940 (Box 116, Folder 3)
  - Waynesboro Nurseries 1951 (Box 116, Folder 4)
  - Wayside Gardens 1944-1965 (Box 116, Folder 5)
  - Westron, Corp. 1957-1965 (Box 116, Folder 6)
  - White Flower Farm 1964-1966 (Box 116, Folder 7)
  - Wohlert, H.E. 1932 (Box 116, Folder 8)
  - Wood-Howell Nurseries, Inc. n.d. (Box 116, Folder 9)
  - Wright, Johnson & Wilkerson, AIA n.d. (Box 116, Folder 10)
  - Zoysia Lawns n.d. (Box 116, Folder 11)
  - OVERSIZE 1952, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)